(Xiang Xiang
Born on June 12,
2017 at Ueno Zoo
in Tokyo, Japan)
(After living in Japan for 5 years)
(Xiang Xiang is about to return to China)
Xiang Xiang! Xiang Xiang!
(Ya'an, China
China Conservation and Research Center
for the Giant Panda, Ya'an Base)
Found another
bamboo shoot
She's very smart but also quite timid
(Princess on the Scene)
and sensitive to sound
Xiang Xiang!
(Xiang Xiang)
I'll give you a massage
Comfy?
(Comfy?)
She runs so fast
Slow down, Xiang Xiang
(Back Home!
Panda Princess Xiang Xiang)
(February 2023
Tokyo, Japan)
(5:14 AM)
I left home a little past 4 AM today
(Takashi Takahiro)
(Webpage Designer
Xiang Xiang's Fan)
Every time I get to see Xiang Xiang means one day closer to farewell
So I wanted to arrive early
I don't want to miss even a second to see Xiang Xiang
It’s only minus one degree (Celsius) at 5 AM in Tokyo
(Ueno Zoo
Located at Taito City, Tokyo, Japan
Opens at 9:30 AM
Closes Every Monday)
But there's already a long line at the Ueno Zoo
Panda exhibit visits
require lottery reservations this month
and the winning rate is only 4%
People wait in line for 4 hours just for a 2-minute visit
These lucky and eager fans have only one wish
to see Xiang Xiang one last time
before she leaves Japan
(Princess Xiang Xiang
on the Scene)
I don't want to miss a single precious moment of Xiang Xiang
(Credit: Tokyo Zoological Park Society)
I took a lot of photos
Over 10,000 today
The queue to see Xiang Xiang is always so long
Xiang Xiang has that charm
No matter how many times or how long I wait
I still want to see her
(February 21, 2023)
The giant panda Xiang Xiang ended her stay in Japan on February 21, 2023
This beloved treasure of the Japanese people is about to embark on the journey to return home
Xiang Xiang!
(Sichuan)
(February 21, 2023
Chengdu, China)
To preserve genetic diversity
pandas born abroad must return to China at the agreed time
Xiang Xiang was supposed to return at age 2
(February 21, 2023
Ya'an, China)
but remained abroad until 5 due to various reasons
Will she like this place?
Her reaction to stress is too intense
Hey
Xiang Xiang, what's the matter?
(Where Am I?)
(So Spacious!)
Even an elegant princess may lose her composure
On the first day, the unfamiliar environment made her dizzy
Take deep breaths, Xiang Xiang
Don't be nervous. Relax
(Ya'an, China
China Conservation and Research Center
for the Giant Panda, Ya'an Base)
(Xiang Xiang's Quarantine Area)
Xiang Xiang will start her new life
at the Ya'an Base of the CCRCGP
Over 60 giant pandas live here
and each one has its own luxurious house
(Heard There's a New Neighbor Next Door)
with a private backyard
(Seems She Came Back from Japan)
Look
(Wow, a Gorgeous Giant Panda)
They take walks here
enjoy themselves, practice kung fu
(Time to Impress Her)
as well as enjoy their social lives
(Can I Add You on WeChat?)
But the introvert Xiang Xiang
stays alone in quarantine
Her spirits are down
Xiang Xiang. Don't be afraid
(Don't Call me. I'm an Introvert Panda)
Don't fret. One step at a time
We'll wait for you
(Quarantine
During the Early Stage When Giant Pandas Return from Overseas
They First Need to Enter a Special Site for Quarantine
This Usually Lasts for 1-2 Months)
(February 2023
Quarantine)
To help Xiang Xiang
adjust to Ya'an Base and the local dialect
the Center
(Princess Xiang Xiang's Bedroom)
arranged for
an experienced "nanny"
to take care of Xiang Xiang
(Two-Bedroom Apartment)
Xiang Xiang
What are you doing?
(Who Are You?)
Huh? Sichuan dialect?
Can Xiang Xiang understand?
Xiang Xiang
What are you doing, Xiang Xiang?
(Keeper, China Conservation and
Research Center for the Giant Panda)
(Zhao Lanlan)
Xiang Xiang
Come here
(Scared)
Xiang Xiang
(Can't Understand)
My first impression was it was a fierce panda
It roared loudly at me as soon as I entered
(Keeper, China Conservation and
Research Center for the Giant Panda)
(Zhao Lanlan)
as if she was frantic
I thought she wasn't docile
(What Are You Talking About?)
What?
It's only me
You're unhappy?
You're not happy
I was quite afraid of her
I was afraid she might scratch me or something
She was probably scared of me too
Xiang Xiang, stop walking around
Xiang Xiang
(Xiang Xiang)
Come here
Xiang Xiang, come here, hurry
Every morning when I clean her room, she'd start running inside
Her reaction to stress is really intense, I'm afraid she'd scratch me
She'd rush over
She'll sprint to you when she sees you
Alas
Meeting for the first time with a language barrier and don't get along
How to break the ice?
(Idea No.1 to Break the Ice
Listen up! Sichuan Dialect)
Xiang Xiang
(Sneak on Some Water)
(Is Someone Calling Me?)
Come
Come here
Come here, hurry
Come eat this
(Are You Calling Me?)
Come here
She's very timid and afraid of strangers
At first, she didn't listen to me. She ignored me
I wanted to reassure her and give her something to eat
I know she liked to eat that
(Keeper, China Conservation and
Research Center for the Giant Panda)
(Zhao Lanlan)
But she wouldn't take anything from me
She was just restless
I called her in Sichuan dialect from the start
I called her name to help her get familiar
with my voice sooner
Come here
This way, over here. It's alright
(Why Are You Everywhere?)
Come here
Come
Hurry
(Come Here Xiang Xiang)
Xiang Xiang
Over here
(You're Such a Nag)
You're leaving again
Slow down, Xiang Xiang
(I Don't Mean to be Mean)
(I'm Just an Introvert Panda)
(Give Me Some Space)
Well
Looks like she didn't realize Sichuan dialect was in her blood
Go for it, Lanlan
(Idea No.2 to Break the Ice
The Attractiveness of Bamboo Shoots)
Xiang Xiang
(Xiang Xiang)
Big bamboo shoots
Are you interested?
Come
it's meal time, princess
(Walk Away Without Hesitation)
This panda is really weird
She can go days without eating when hungry
She'd only take some water without touching your food
Other pandas would eat when they're hungry
(Keeper, China Conservation and
Research Center for the Giant Panda)
(Zhao Lanlan)
They'd at least eat something in two days
but this panda didn't eat in three days
Xiang Xiang
it's not good to be so picky
We're worried about your health
It's not good for your health if you don't eat
Xiang Xiang
No need to run away, come here
I learned from her living habits in Japan
that she enjoyed eating a kind of bamboo called the Sinobambusa
So I thought
(Keeper, China Conservation and
Research Center for the Giant Panda)
(Zhao Lanlan)
well this panda might like to eat bamboo leaves
I thought that
our bamboo leaves were excellent
especially the tender bitter bamboo leaves
(Idea No.3 to Break the Ice
Charm of Bamboo Leaves)
Lanlan
you're really resourceful
Xiang Xiang should take you in this time
Come for some bamboo
Smell it
Do you want these?
Where are you pulling them to?
Are you mad?
You don't want this?
(Smells Awesome)
(Eat It)
Try it
Fresh leaves
See?
(Should I Eat It?)
Try it
(Really Tempting)
Don't get mad
(Almost Fell for It)
Be gentle
She didn't eat it
(Keeper, China Conservation and
Research Center for the Giant Panda)
(Zhao Lanlan)
I wondered what was going on
She wouldn't eat it
So I thought why not let it try the bamboo around here
Xiang Xiang
I took another type of bamboo here
Come
(Idea No.4 to Break the Ice
Strike of the Bamboo Culm)
Smell it
Hurry up and eat it
Hurry
Do you want it?
Do you want some bamboo?
(Same Old Trick)
You pushed it away
You don't want this? Still don't want this?
I'll give you another one
Xiang Xiang, I brought another for you
Come smell it
Smell it
Smell it. This bamboo is quite nice. That's right
(Not Bad)
Come
Fetch it
Eat it
(Eat it)
C'mon, give it a try.
(Let Me Think About It)
Please, fetch it and take it away
Just take a bite.
We have green bamboo
golden bamboo, moso bamboo
square bamboo, and broad-leaf bamboo
At our base, only pandas awaiting childbirth
(Keeper, China Conservation and
Research Center for the Giant Panda)
(Zhao Lanlan)
are given square bamboo to eat
But she wouldn't eat anything at all
According to our initial analysis
this may be caused by her being
over-delicately taken care of in Japan
No wonder people call you Princess Xiang Xiang
I wonder what the lifestyle of a princess was like
How much did the Japanese people love giant pandas?
(Film)
Actually, before Xiang Xiang was born
there had already been a "panda fever" in Japan
and the first arrival of giant pandas "Kang Kang" and "Lan Lan"
caused a huge sensation
On the first day the panda house opened, more than 50,000 people came to watch her
There was no way to get a ticket at all
In 2017, the birth of a little one
brought the long-lasting "panda fever"
to a new climax
This little guy in the limelight
was born less than 15 centimeters
only 147 grams, smaller than the size of a palm
She was all pink and so cute
Regardless of the era
(Deputy Director, Ueno Zoo)
(Yasumasa Tomita)
whenever a giant panda is born
it attracts the attention of the society
Xiang Xiang is also
a very special female panda in this world
People were really cautious every day
(Deputy Director, Ueno Zoo)
(Yasumasa Tomita)
wondering if they could take good care of her
As a hard-earned child of the Ueno Zoo
since the moment she was born
she has captured the attention of the entire Japan
To name her
Tokyo sought proposals nationwide
and countless Japanese people showed their support
In the end, the name "Xiang Xiang"
was chosen from 320,000 proposals
Since then, the little princess entered the spotlight
Xiang Xiang grew up
under the loving care of the Ueno Zoo
The Japanese public saw her grow her first teeth
witnessed her first toddler steps
watched her pamper
and learn to run
Alas
Xiang Xiang, you're so naughty
(Xiang Xiang, 5 Months Old)
(Xiang Xiang, 8 Months Old)
Year after year
every moment of Xiang Xiang's growth
(Xiang Xiang, 1 Year Old)
became a cherished memory
for many fans
(Xiang Xiang, 1.5 Years Old)
(Xiang Xiang, 2 Years Old)
(Xiang Xiang, 3 Years Old)
(Tokyo, Japan
Takashi Takahiro's Residence)
I took a lot of photos today
but it seems like there's nothing of worth
I usually take 5,000 to 10,000 photos a day on average
and I pick 100 photos to upload to social media
So many panda photos
He's really a hardcore fan of Xiang Xiang
It's said that since 2011
Takashi Takahiro has visited Ueno Zoo daily
to photograph the pandas
After Xiang Xiang was born
he documented her growth
This photo was taken
during her first public appearance
She likes to hang herself on this branch
She loves this stump
She always hugs it
basically sleeping all the time
This photo was taken when she was awake
with her eyes wide open
and expressions so cute
This is Xiang Xiang
A Xiang Xiang doll
This is another one
It's her twin Lei Lei
Is there any difference between the twins?
There's nothing different
They're really the same
This was made according to
how they looked after they were born a week
And the weight was also customized
according to their own weights
after they were born a week
I wanted to meet Xiang Xiang earlier
However
I had to give Xiang Xiang some time
Hopefully, she would adapt soon
I hope that everyone can see a healthy Xiang Xiang
(Ya'an, China
China Conservation and Research Center
for the Giant Panda, Ya'an Base)
The weather is great today
Has Xiang Xiang grown some appetite?
We heard that when Lanlan wasn't around
she snuck some food for herself
Hi
You didn't eat a lot of bamboo last night
Xiang Xiang
It's a new day
Our expert breeding group
did a rough analysis
and concluded that if she
came back when she was one to two years old
she would be in the learning stage
But now that she's back
she's already 5 years old
So she might need
more time to adapt
Her discomfort
is due to missing the best time to learn
Catching up is certainly exhausting
Go for it, Xiang Xiang
When I learned that I'd be Xiang Xiang's keeper
when she returns
I started to pay attention to her
I've tended to
more than 100 giant pandas
at her stage
We feed her by our standards
and ease her into the transition
There has to be a process
Xiang Xiang's new home is in Bifengxia Town, Ya'an
right next to the habitat of over 300 wild giant pandas
The pandas living here
spend their days either eating
or lying around
or
lying around while eating
Oh
and there's rolling
Look
They even have Bifengxia colors
(Bifengxia Colors)
At first
I only knew that she enjoyed apples
So I cut the apples into small slices
I'd feed one apple to her in four portions
With more feeding sessions
she'd get used to my voice
and my smell
This way
she can gradually let down her guard
Xiang Xiang
(Idea No. N to Break the Ice
Sweet Apples)
Xiang Xiang
Xiang Xiang, I'm here
(Let's See What You Got Today)
I have apples today, come here
Xiang Xiang
(Get on the Scale)
Get on the scale, Xiang Xiang
Come here
Luring the panda to hop on the scale
What a nice trick
Come over here
Eat it
(Let Me Taste It)
Get on the scale
Looks like
apples work the best
Look
She's on the scale
100 kilograms
She sneakily gained 6 kilos
(Tastes Awesome)
Eat it
We try our best to meet her needs
What else can we do?
I have to make sure she's healthy
At least make sure she gets enough to eat, right?
Lanlan and Xiang Xiang are becoming closer
You can feel the nanny's love even across the screen
Get some bamboo shoots
Two over here
Fresh bamboo shoots
Eat it
(I Give in)
Smell it
I tried almost every kind of bamboo around the park
(A Basket Full of Love)
and brought them here to let her try them
I found out she liked the ornamental
Golden Bamboo the most and the Bitter bamboo's culms
Come here
(Success in Breaking the Ice!)
Turns out
to win a princess over is not the privilege of a prince
A painstaking nanny can also make it.
You were grumpy because
you didn't want to eat my bamboo
and you only wanted the shoots?
Our center demands us
to follow the standardized procedures
However, when it comes to specifics
I would try to satisfy her needs
(Keeper, China Conservation and
Research Center for the Giant Panda)
(Zhao Lanlan)
I'd feed her well
make sure she enjoys her food
and stays healthy
(Spit It Out +1)
(Spit It Out +2)
(Spit It Out +3)
Such a waste
(Such a Waste)
So many leftovers
You have to finish them all
Don't let it go to waste
(Happy Meal Times
for a Foodie Panda)
If you finish it. I'll give you another one
Just come inside
(One More Basket)
Grab more bamboo shoots
Xiang Xiang
Lanlan treats you like first love
but you see her as a restaurant waitress
It's alright. Eat it
Poor bamboo shoots in the backyard
destined to be eaten by the panda
Eat it
There's more here
(Another Basket)
(Gained More Weight)
Eat it
Finally
when I call her name, she would respond to me
She would look at me
She was able to respond to me
After she gradually got used to me
she didn't walk as rapidly as before
(Keeper, China Conservation and
Research Center for the Giant Panda)
(Zhao Lanlan)
and I tried to feed her with my hands
(May 2023)
Xiang Xiang
(Xiang Xiang)
Come here
(Coming)
Come, sit down
Good girl
Come
Over here
Get up now
Come here
Come
Over here
This way
Come
Good girl
Take one
Xiang Xiang
Seems like they're starting to get in sync
Lanlan should finally be relieved now
(Huh?)
Hey
what's wrong, Xiang Xiang?
(What?)
(What now?)
Oh my
Got stuck
Eat it
There's something about her
While eating
just as she seems to be chewing smoothly
(Keeper, China Conservation and
Research Center for the Giant Panda)
(Zhao Lanlan)
she suddenly pauses
and listens intently
Eat it
This panda
is really sensitive to sounds
Once, an unknown bird call
scared her
When frightened, she tends to pace around frequently
and needs a very long time to calm down
Usually, some pandas would calm down
in about half an hour
But not her
she might take an hour and a half two hours
or even longer
I studied her past
Since birth, she has always stayed
in the same place, never moved
So, the environment here is different for her
Took a lot of effort to take Lanlan in
but now she's stuck with weird sounds
It's really difficult to move on with new things
Go for it, Xiang Xiang
It's just raining
It's raining
It's nothing
Eat it
She's very smart
Exceptionally smart
Maybe it's because she's too smart
so she's very sensitive to sounds
Eat it
It's nothing
Oh no
Turned into a frozen panda
Eat it
You have to tell her
It's nothing
Take it slowly
It's only me
Talk to her like that and she'd slowly start to eat
Eat it
(Gorgeous Panda
Eating Show Livestream)
(Secretly Swap a Bamboo Shoot)
Hey, you didn't finish that one
(Another One)
What's wrong with you
You haven't finished the last one
Froze again
(Not a JPG)
Eat it
Xiang Xiang
you've almost turned into a PowerPoint
(Not a JPG +1)
Eat it
(Eat It)
Birds chirping
It's nothing
Eat your food
Eat it
It's only me
Lanlan is so gentle
When she hears her calling
Xiang Xiang would relax
(Eat It)
(It's Nothing)
(It's Only Me)
Let me scratch you
Rub you
Massage you
Feels good?
Feels good, right?
You're leaving
Finished your food?
Feels good?
Another day finished
Eat some more bamboo shoots tonight
(Okay!)
I'm leaving
I'll come back tomorrow
(June 10, 2023)
Hurry up. It's falling down
Oh
It's falling down
Watch your step.
What?
What are they doing?
Building a house
Oh
They're going to throw a birthday party for Xiang Xiang
So lively
Hey
(Tokyo, Japan
Xiang Xiang's Birthday Party)
Fans in Japan are also celebrating Xiang Xiang's birthday
I made a lot of friends who are also panda fans
(Takashi Takahiro)
(Webpage Designer
Xiang Xiang's Fan)
With like-minded friends
celebrating Xiang Xiang's birthday together is truly joyful
Whenever I see Xiang Xiang
I'd forget about the sadness and loneliness
I'd just think of how cute she is
I really want to visit China sooner to see Xiang Xiang
Today is Xiang Xiang's 6-year-old birthday
We made a model cake out of bamboo
I wish she'd be healthy and everything goes well
for her in the future
Put an apple on top
Wish for good fortune
Xiang Xiang
Go out now. Hurry
Look at all those fat on you
It's alright
Move on, go out
Xiang Xiang, time to go out for your meal
(Xiang Xiang, time to go out for your meal)
Xiang Xiang
We've made a cake for you
(Something's Not Right)
How is it?
Do you like it?
Are you surprised?
(What?)
(Double Check)
There are two butterflies
The cake is very attractive
(Hesitant)
(Maybe Next Time)
Hey. Don't go away, Xiang Xiang
Try this cake Lanlan made for you
(What's a Cake?)
(Xiang Xiang)
Xiang Xiang
(Don't Know Where to Put My Paw)
Try the cake I made you
Xiang Xiang
It's alright. It's all yours
Xiang Xiang, come here
Over here, Xiang Xiang
Not even the apple?
Come here, Xiang Xiang
She looked at the cake we made
but she didn't go for it
I'm a little disappointed
but she'll maybe have it this afternoon
Over here, Xiang Xiang
She's still getting familiar with her new environment
and she will eventually eat what we've provided
Xiang Xiang
(I'm Here)
I was very glad that
when I called her name
she looked at me
She turned back and looked at me
We've further established our trust
Xiang Xiang
I'm back again
Worried that Xiang Xiang hasn't fed
Lanlan brought some snacks back to her
Here
Xiang Xiang
Eat your bamboo shoots
Eat it
Over here
It's alright
It's only me
After four months
the introvert Xiang Xiang
not only made friends with Lanlan
but also became braver
She can already enjoy a walk now
And she's getting accustomed
to the coziness of her hometown
(Bifengxia Colors)
I've been taking care of her
since her return
I almost never take a leave from work
Because if someone else came
her emotions would become unpredictable
I was so worried about her
But now she's doing much better
However
there's still one sound
that scares Xiang Xiang away instantly
(Something's Wrong?)
(Let Me See Who It Is)
(I'm Doomed. Must Go Now)
(He Found Me)
(Cheng Yanxi)
(China Conservation and Research Center
for the Giant Panda, Panda Doctor)
She knows I'm here
She's in that bush now
I can only see one ear
It's as if she's erecting her ears to listen
(Oh My, My Ear Gave Me Away)
She's moving to another place
She gets anxious when she hears me
and wants to run away
(Don't Suppose He Can Still See Me Here)
(Can't See Me…)
(Oh No, Still Found Me)
I did a body check for her before
so she probably still remembers me
from the shot I gave her
She's doing fine lately
She's just a little timid
Nothing else major
(Go and Inspect the Other Pandas)
Sit straight
Let me check
Sit over here
Good girl. Here you go
At the Ya'an Base
there is also a "nursery team" of panda specialists
who have been looking after the pandas
Sit here and let me check on you
Cheng Yanxi, the "panda doctor"
inspects the enclosure every day
Look, listen, question, and diagnose
Every giant panda here
never has to worry about the difficulty of seeing a doctor
no matter what condition they have
However
he's also the one person
that many giant pandas hate to see
There you go
Of course, they dislike me
Treating them naturally makes them hate me
It's just like kids hate
visiting the hospital
But they still must go
Right?
It's alright if they hate me
That's still better than getting sick
You're enjoying the food so much
The panda experts at the base
have been observing and evaluating
and are expecting Xiang Xiang
to end her quarantine sooner
She likes to stay at these spots around here
(Looking at Me Again)
It's quiet up there
Yes
Every day
it's remote
Yes. It's also far from the outside
That's why she likes that spot the most
Yeah. Yes
Is she alright, Dr. Cheng?
It's alright
Oh
Xiang Xiang
Dr. Cheng says you're healthy
You might be chubby
but you're strong
(August 2023)
Every returning panda must undergo quarantine
before officially joining the base
After nearly 6 months of trials and tribulations
Xiang Xiang has finally adapted to the environment of the base
It's been a rough journey, Xiang Xiang
Congratulations
You've made it
As a reward
she'll of course
get a new house
Xiang Xiang
Come here
Get in
I'm here
It's alright
Don't be afraid
It's fine
(Lanlan, Where Are You Taking Me?)
It's alright, Xiang Xiang. It's fine
The moving went smoothly
Xiang Xiang
You're amazing today
You've made great progress
(I'll Check My New Residence)
Your new house is very spacious
The entire hill is yours
And you have floor-to-ceiling windows
that block quite a lot of sound
It's really quiet
Xiang Xiang
This is all tailor-made for you
Take some good rest
(So Comfortable)
Soon enough
you'd be ready to officially meet with everyone
(Looking Forward to It)
(August 2023)
(September 2023)
(New Residence)
(October 7, 2023)
Hey. Lanlan is starting to clean the windows
Could it be?
(Enclosure Under Construction
Move Ahead to Continue Your Tour)
(Xiang Xiang
Gender: Female
Date of Birth: June 12, 2017
Place of Birth: Ueno Zoo, Tokyo, Japan)
Xiang Xiang is finally going to meet everyone
The over 200-day adaptation period at home
is truly a long wait
So exciting
(I'm also excited)
I was quite excited
(Great News
Xiang Xiang officially met with
all visitors on October 9, 2023
at the Ya'an Base)
I couldn't sleep until 3 or 4 in the late night
and woke up at 6 o'clock this morning
Xiang Xiang is really cute
I think she's acting a lot better than before
I hope she quickly adapts to China's environment
and finds an ideal mate
Awesome, Xiang Xiang
Your first public appearance in China
won countless fans
("Hello China" Tourism Promotion Logo Launch
Giant Panda "Xiang Xiang" Japanese Family and Friends Group Pre-departure Meeting)
(November 6, 2023)
Since Xiang Xiang returned to China in February
I always wanted to meet Xiang Xiang again
I thought about when I could see Xiang Xiang every day
3,400 kilometers away
her eager Japanese fans have been
impatiently waiting to see her
(Hello China)
Xiang Xiang
We're coming!
(Sichuan)
(Hello China, Cozy Sichuan
Japanese Friends Group's Visit to Giant Panda Xiang Xiang)
Wow
Panda cakes
Panda tea cups
And panda embroideries
So many pandas
What?
A panda climbing to the rooftop?
Hold on!
He just turned into a panda face
This is amazing
This is indeed the hometown of pandas
(November 8, 2023
Ya'an, China)
I was so excited the night before our departure
I was so nervous and didn't sleep well
I'm actually very afraid of flights
I only made up my mind
to take the plane to Sichuan because I wanted to see Xiang Xiang
My wish to see Xiang Xiang
is growing more intense by the second
I'm already very anxious
The roads of Sichuan are as hard to scale as the skies
Seems like to meet with Xiang Xiang
you'd always have a plethora of companions every time
Xiang Xiang has reached a place
so much farther than I've imagined
It's quiet
and spacious
Just like mountains, there are highs and lows
An ideal place for Xiang Xiang
Wow
So many people
This is panda
The backpack has a panda
This is her paw
You're all from Japan?
Yes, we're from Japan
Just want to see Xiang Xiang
You missed her so much?
Every day
Seeing her used to take two or three hours of waiting
No matter how long it takes, I'll wait
Don't worry, Mr. Takashi, it won't take long
The princess
will arrive shortly
I suppose she'll come out of that tunnel
She's coming
Xiang Xiang is coming
With steps so confident and elegant
the "International Xiang" is indeed one of her kind
I was shocked when I first saw Xiang Xiang
When I saw her sitting down and starting to eat
(So Many People Today)
I was so moved that tears filled my eyes
In order to not disturb Xiang Xiang
everyone is so quiet
Just want to see her once more
see more of her
Her every move
and every expression
is the greatest reward to her fans
Seeing Xiang Xiang again after eight months
I feel she's grown up
(Filmed by Takashi Takahiro)
I saw her chubby tummy
when she was drinking
Xiang Xiang is six years old
Time to look for a mate for life
The meeting is so short this time
I hope that when I see Xiang Xiang next time
I can stay for a week or two weeks
Stay for a longer time
Xiang Xiang, come here
Really haven't seen her for a long time
My eyes are filled with tears
She's eating so happily
I can feel how happy she is
I feel very satisfied within
(Xiang Xiang
Gender: Female
Date of Birth: June 12, 2017
Place of Birth: Ueno Zoo, Tokyo, Japan)
Xiang Xiang
See if I can find her
Xiang Xiang!
So slippery
Baby!
Baby means I'm calling Xiang Xiang
because I'm used to calling her that
So I didn't change it
It also shows my affection for her
Baby, come out now
Baby
She's coming down
Oh my
She's running so fast
From initial strangers
to now running eagerly towards each other
Xiang Xiang and Lanlan have overcome
many obstacles to become close companions
Slow down
Xiang Xiang
Come in now
Sit
Sichuan dialect?
Sit tight
Got it
Awesome
That's right
Good girl
Xiang Xiang
I've fed you for a while now
right?
They all call you princess
Princess Xiang Xiang
they say you were pink
when you were a kid
Your mother loves you
You'll also become a mother
got it?
You can't be picky about your food
Don't be too picky
Otherwise, you won't be healthy
Get out now
She's an introvert panda that
you normally wouldn't see in a century
and she's become my responsibility
Even though she causes me a lot of trouble
I still like her quite a lot
Now she's finally able to meet with the visitors
This entire process
was very prolonged
but for me, it was exhausting but cheerful
I'm very satisfied
That's how I feel
Rest assured, Lanlan, the princess has grown up
Because of your company
Xiang Xiang is now used to the life in her hometown
She's now braver and more confident
But Xiang Xiang and Lanlan's story
isn't over yet
Oh right
soon enough
Princess Xiang Xiang might become a mother
And
who will be her prince?
(Lanlan, Can I Climb Up
These Stairs?)
(Xiang Xiang, I Dare You!)
(I'll Always Keep an Eye on You!)
(Lanlan,
Watch Me Climb!)
(Xiang Xiang, Be Careful!)
(It's Alright,
I Like to Climb to High Places)
(I'll Be Watching You from Here.
You're Fine!)
(Xiang Xiang,
Slow Down.
You're Allowed to Take a Break)
(I Must Keep Striving,
Because…)
(I Want to Let You See
That I Will Grow up Healthy!)
(Alright!)
(We Will Meet Again!)